THOMAS BURNS

(860) 550-1731

tcburns24@gmail.com





Profile

A software developer bringing six years of experience in education and intercultural communication. I'm eager to bring my love for software into a team setting and explore development at the company level.

Tech Skills

Java JavaScript

Ruby

SQL

Rails

Git Angular

Projects

I) WIKIONE Oct 2016

A wikipedia clone built with Ruby on Rails, styled with bootstrap.

II) BLOCCITOFF Nov 2016

A self-destructing to-do list app built with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, styled with bootstrap.

III) HANGMAN Jul 2017

A classic two player game written in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

Experience

ROBOTERRA, INC.SANTA CLARA, CA
DIRECTOR OF EDUCATION
JUN 2015 - JUN 2016

- Started the company's Education Department | Annual \$80,000 budget
- Spoke at CES 2016 on robotics education

HALSTROM ACADEMY

HEAD OF SCHOOL

Increased student body by 400%

CUPERTINO, CA AUG 2014 - JUN 2015

GRANBY, MA

AUG 2012 - JUN 2014

THE MACDUFFIE SCHOOL

MANDARIN CHINESE TEACHER

Designed and taught school's first Mandarin Chinese course

TEACH FOR AMERICA

SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER

PHOENIX, AZ & NEW YORK, NY JUN 2010 - JUN 2012

• Designed and taught Special Education Math, Reading and Writing curricula for grades; resulted in 100% students increasing scores on Arizona end-of-year standardized assessment.

Education

BLOCSOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROGRAM

SAN JOSE, CA JUL 2016 - SEP 2017

UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS AMHERST

M.A. CHINESE LANGUAGE AND LITERATURE B.A. CHINESE LANGUAGE AND LITERATURE

AMHERST, MA SEP 2012 - JUN 2014 JAN 2007 - MAY 2010

MINZU UNIVERSITY OF CHINA (北京中央民族大学)

FULBRIGHT SCHOLARSHIP

BEIJING, CHINA JUN 2013 - AUG 2013